Fatjon Rrapaj

Senior React Native Developer fatjonrrapaj@live.com • +355685919978 https://fatjonrrapaj.netlify.app/

Summary

I am a React JS & React Native Developer with 6 years of commercial experience of developing mobile apps and websites. I always strive to write highly human-readable and highly machine-performant code that makes up highly-valuable applications that are delivered quickly.

Skills

Mobile development • Front end development • React • React native • JavaScript • TypeScript • Android • iOS

Work Experience

Senior React Native Developer

Jul 2022 - Present

Cinolla • Part Time

London, UK (Remote)

Technologies: React Native ● JavaScript ● Figma

Continuously UI UX Designing and developing a React Native App based on company's and client's specifications.

Senior React Native Developer

Aug 2022 - Mar 2023 • 6 mos

Open English • Full-time

Chicago, US (Remote)

Technologies: React Native • React • TypeScript • Jenkins

Initially worked on their React Native App Made for Kids (Open English Junior).

Building Activities With React Native Expo & React Native Expo Web, and writing all of the End to End tests for the App. Taking advantage of React Native Expo Web, I used Cypress to test React Native Apps, which was amazing.

After that, released the first version of Open Mundo App, Moving from multiple Apps to Monorepo, while maintaining the App in production with bug-fixes, feature adding etc.

Frontend tech leader Jan 2022 - Jul 2022 • 6 mos

Stalmarck Resources Optimization • Full-time

Stockholm, Sweden (Remote)

Technologies: TypeScript • React • Socket.IO • Tailwindcss

In charge of the frontend Applications, provided various solutions, mostly selecting the needed technologies for their Applications & their business model/way of working, and setting them up for their first version of their major clients presentation.

Freelance React Native Developer

May 2021 - Jan 2022 • 8 mos

Freelance • Freelance

Remote

Technologies: React Native • Firebase • JavaScript • Figma • TypeScript

Building React Native Apps from scratch for Clients using React Native & Firebase.

React Native & React JS Developer

Sep 2020 - Jun 2021 • 9 mos

BetterSpace • Full-time

London, UK (Remote)

Technologies: React Native • React • JavaScript • Stripe

Developing from scratch and publishing new web and mobile applications using React JS and React Native. Adding test coverage for both web and mobile applications.

160 Driving Academy • Full-time

Tirana, Albania

Technologies: React Native • React • Firebase

Developed from scratch and publishing new web and mobile applications using React JS and React Native. Added test coverage for both web and mobile applications.

iOS Developer Jun 2018 - Mar 2019 • 9 mos

Softmogul • Full-time

Tirana, Albania

Technologies: iOS • Swift • gRPC • Docker • Xcode

Developed iOS app using Swift and Xcode /Performed technical designs and implementations of 4+ complex iOS apps / Built Airdrop-like functionality using gRPC and Apple Multipeer Connectivity / Massive code refactoring from MVC to MVVM,MVVM-C,RxSwift / App performance testing/ Refactored testable-friendly environment / Built internal pod to increase reusability.

Android Developer Nov 2017 - Jun 2018 • 7 mos

Baboon • Full-time

Tirana, Albania

Technologies: Java • Android studio

Designed and developed Android apps using Java and

Android Studio. Used different Java Design Patterns as MVP, Observer Pattern etc. Developed solutions to help reducing business costs.

Projects

My 3d portfolio (ongoing)

2022

Technologies: Three.js • React • Blender

Learning and applying Three JS and react-three-fiber and playing around with blender while building my 3d portfolio.

The current texts and object are still placeholders,.

Educations

Bachelor's degree: Business Informatics

Oct 2015 - Jul 2018 • 2 yrs 9 mos

European University of Tirana

Tirana, Albania Grade/GPA: 9.2

Certifications & Awards

Best Business Idea & Development Plan - European University of Tirana

Mar 2018

Languages

English (Professional working proficiency)

Italian (Limited working proficiency)